Inventory of the Garland R. Farmer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Garland R. Farmer papers
1946-1992
91080
Hoover Institution Archives
50 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (20.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, business and financial records, bulletins, statistical data, pamphlets, serial issues, clippings, other printed matter, and photographs relating to iron ore mining in Liberia and to political, social, and economic conditions in Liberia. Includes some material relating to Ghana and other countries of Africa, and to Lansdell K. Christie, founder of the Liberia Mining Company.
Farmer, Garland R.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Garland Farmer, an American businessman, was an industrialist and miner in West Africa, specifically Liberia, who specialized in iron ore mining. He was affiliated with several large African mining companies, including the National Iron Ore Company and Mine Management Associates, Limited, serving as president of the latter.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists largely of business-related documents, correspondence, and images relating to iron ore mining in Liberia. Additional material relates to political, social, and economic conditions in Liberia, and some material relating to Ghana and other countries of Africa, and to Lansdell K. Christie, founder of the Liberia Mining Company, is included as well.
The original order and folder titles of the creator have largely been maintained, with a few exceptions. Folder titles or explanatory information added by the archivist have been marked with square brackets.
Christie, Lansdell K., dd. 1965.; Liberia Mining Company.; Mine Management Associates.; Ghana.; Iron mines and mining--Liberia.; Liberia--Economic conditions.; Liberia--Politics and government.; Liberia--Social conditions.
- [Various newspaper clippings], 1971-1974 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- [Biography of Lansdell K. Christie], 1990 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- [Assorted documents on Liberia and Nigeria], 1960-1987 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- [Assorted documents on Liberian economy and history], 1963-1991 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- [Report on the tax system of Liberia], 1969 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- African art documents, 1960s (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Television and radio, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- Textiles, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Transportation, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Financial - private banks in Africa, 1965-1975 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Fertilizers, 1962-1976 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Art, culture, folklore, 1963-1984 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Guinea, 1960-1983 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- Burkina Faso (Upper Volta), 1970s (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Kenya, 1963-1975 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- Libya, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 2: 11)
- Malagasy Republic, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- Malawi, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 2: 13)
- Ivory Coast, 1963-1983 (Box-folder 2: 14)
- Gambia, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Gabon, 1962-1975 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- Mauritania, 1963-1975 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Mali, 1960-1978 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Ethiopia, 1961-1975 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Equatorial Guinea, 1961-1973 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- Chad, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- Central African Republic, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- Cameroon, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 3: 9)
- Burundi, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 3: 10)
- Republic of the Congo, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 3: 11)
- China-Taiwan, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 12)
- Israel, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 3: 13)
- Italy in Africa, 1964-1974 (Box-folder 3: 14)
- Eastern Bloc in Africa, 1961-1978 (Box-folder 3: 15)
- French community, general and political, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 3: 16)
- France and Africa, 1956-1983 (Box-folder 3: 17)
- Algeria, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 4: 1)
- Benin (Dahomey), 1960-1970 (Box-folder 4: 2)
- China - People's Republic, 1960-1980 (Box-folder 4: 3)
- African general history, 1946-1975 (Box-folder 4: 4)
- African religion, 1962-1975 (Box-folder 4: 5)
- African general education, 1969-1983 (Box-folder 4: 6)
- African general health and medicine, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 7)
- Military - armies, coups, 1964-1974 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- Military - Sudan, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 4: 9)
- Military - Nigeria, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 4: 10)
- Military - Morocco, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 4: 11)
- Military - Libya, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 4: 12)
- Military - Ethiopia, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 4: 13)
- [Various Africa background magazines], 1959-1961 (Box-folder 4: 14)
- Pohang Iron and Steel Co. (POSCO) brief, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 15)
- China Steel Corporation (CSC) brief, 1982 (Box-folder 4: 16)
- [Miscellaneous Liberia documents and printed matter], 1959-1970 (Box-folder 5: 1)
- [Memorabilia - deed], 1959-1982 (Box 5)
- Internatio and Müller Company, 1964-1970 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Mano contracts, tonnages shipped, market reports, 1970-1984 (Box-folder 6: 2)
- Miscellaneous correspondence regarding Mano, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 6: 3)
- Articles on Mano, Bomi, and Liberian iron ore, 1960-1974 (Box-folder 6: 4)
- Mano newspaper clippings, 1960-1988 (Box-folder 6: 5)
- Mano - quality, 1966-1984 (Box-folder 6: 6)
- Mano - prices, 1971-1985 (Box-folder 6: 7)
- Mano Y's informant, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 6: 8)
- NIOC [National Iron Ore Company] - reports on activities, 1965-1983 (Box-folder 6: 9)
- NIOC - early documents, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 6: 10)
- NIOC/MMAL [Mine Management Associates, Ltd.]/LMS [Liberian Mining Company] contributions, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 6: 11)
- Miscellaneous Garland Farmer correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 6: 12)
- Photographs - first shipment of Mano ore loaded, Port of Monrovia, 1961 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- Correspondence of R. Van Nordheim, General Manager, MMAL, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 7: 2)
- Mano ore sales contracts and specifications, 1960 (Box-folder 7: 3)
- MMAL correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 7: 4-6)
- Photographs, early 1961 (Box-folder 7: 7)
- W. V. S. Tubman - Garland Farmer, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 8: 1)
- W. V. S. Tubman - miscellaneous, 1952 (Box-folder 8: 2)
- Miscellaneous articles on W. V. S. Tubman, 1960-1973 (Box-folder 8: 3)
- Still photos from movie, undated (Box-folder 8: 4)
- Early Mano, photographs, undated (Box-folder 8: 5)
- L. K. C. [Lansdell K. Christie], W. V. S. T. [W. V. S. Tubman], P. B. [Prince Bernhard] trip to Mano [photographs], 1962 (Box-folder 8: 6)
- Mano II contract signing [photographs], undated (Box-folder 8: 7)
- Mano [photographs], undated (Box-folder 8: 8)
- Mano miscellaneous [photographs], undated (Box-folder 8: 9)
- Mano River mining operations [photographs], undated (Box-folder 8: 10)
- Jungle and mining operations [photographs], undated (Box-folder 8: 11)
- Miscellaneous [photographs], undated (Box-folder 8: 12)
- President Tolbert - Family of Man award, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 1)
- President Tolbert - 1972 inauguration (Box-folder 9: 2)
- President Tolbert - 1976 visit to U.S. (Box-folder 9: 13)
- William Tolbert birthday wishes, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 4)
- William Tolbert speeches and press statements, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 9: 5)
- W. R. Tolbert - (V.P.), 1960s (Box-folder 9: 6)
- W. V. S. Tubman - Visit to U.S., 1968 (Box-folder 9: 7)
- W. V. S. Tubman - African Cooperation (OAU) [Organization of African Unity], 1963-1983 (Box-folder 9: 8)
- W. V. S. Tubman - death, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 9)
- W. V. S. Tubman - miscellaneous statements, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 9: 10)
- W. V. S. Tubman - domestic, tribal matters, etc., 1963-1971 (Box-folder 9: 11)
- W. V. S. Tubman on investment, open door, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 9: 12)
- Garland Farmer-W. R. Tolbert - Liberian agriculture correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 10: 1)
- Power Project Liberia, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 10: 2)
- [Miscellaneous clippings], 1973-1989 (Box-folder 10: 3)
- Globex, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 10: 4)
- Trade and economics, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 10: 5)
- Finance - taxes - government, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 10: 6)
- Self help, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 10: 7)
- Public works, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 10: 8)
- National Fund rally, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 10: 9)
- Minerals - diamonds, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 10: 10)
- W. R. Tolbert - President, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 10: 11-12)
- Health - hospitals (Box-folder 11: 1)
- Low-cost housing, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 11: 2)
- Liberian education, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 11: 3)
- The Liberian Economic and Management Review, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 4)
- Discrimination, bias, etc., 1964-1972 (Box-folder 11: 5)
- Development Bank and Fund, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 11: 6)
- Corruption, 1972-1984 (Box-folder 11: 7)
- Black Americans and Liberia, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 11: 8)
- Liberian government finance, 1962-1987 (Box-folder 11: 9)
- Liberia Investment Incentive Code, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 10)
- Liberian labor, 1963-1975 (Box-folder 11: 11)
- Lebanese in Liberia, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 11: 12)
- Legislation, legislature, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 11: 13)
- Liberianization, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 11: 14)
- Liberian - minerals, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 11: 15)
- Gateway to West Africa, 1970s (Box-folder 12: 1)
- Foreign aid, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 12: 2)
- [General articles/publications on Liberia], 1960-1976 (Box-folder 12: 3)
- W. V. S Tubman - 70th birthday, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 4)
- W. V. S. Tubman - Silver Anniversary as President, 1969 (Box-folder 12: 5)
- Liberia 1968 inauguration (Box-folder 12: 6)
- W. V. S. Tubman visit to U.S., 1961 (Box-folder 12: 7)
- U.S. aid to Liberia, 1955-1973 (Box-folder 12: 8)
- Liberian economy, general, 1960-1983 (Box-folder 12: 9)
- W. V. S. Tubman speeches, 1946-1971 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
- W. V. S. Tubman, Sanniquellie Conference dinner in Holland photographs, undated (Box-folder 13: 3)
- 1960 inauguration (Box-folder 13: 4)
- 1952 inauguration (Box-folder 13: 5)
- Material for 1960 U.S. visit (Box-folder 13: 6)
- 1964 inauguration (Box-folder 13: 7)
- G. R. Farmer correspondence, 1972 August-December (Box-folder 14: 1)
- Mano reports and correspondence, 1973 July-December (Box-folder 14: 2)
- Correspondence, 1972 August - 1973 August (Box-folder 14: 3)
- Correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 14: 4)
- Mano correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 14: 5)
- Mano reports and correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 14: 6)
- General correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 14: 7)
- Mano mine disaster reports, 1982 (Box-folder 14: 8)
- Railroads and trackage, 1973 (Box-folder 14: 9)
- Mano reports, 1971 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
- Mano reports and correspondence - 1st half, 1972 (Box-folder 15: 3)
- Mano correspondence - 2nd half, 1972 (Box-folder 15: 4)
- Correspondence - 1st half, 1972 (Box-folder 15: 5)
- Mano monthly and annual reports, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 15: 6)
- Liberia-U.S. relations, 1966-1986 (Box-folder 16: 1)
- Liberia foreign relations, state visits, etc., 1961-1983 (Box-folder 16: 2)
- Politics (assassination attempts, sedition), 1960-1973 (Box-folder 16: 3)
- Press - newspapers, etc., journalists (Liberian and foreign), 1971-1973 (Box-folder 16: 4)
- Liberia bibliography, 1963-1978 (Box-folder 16: 5)
- Liberian immigration/citizenship, 1974 (Box-folder 16: 6)
- Miscellaneous Liberia, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 16: 7)
- Politics and elections, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 16: 8)
- Politics - The Revelation, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 16: 9)
- Liberian politics/Tubman government, 1960-1973 (Box-folder 16: 10)
- East Africa cooperation (Common Services), PAFMECSA [Pan-African Freedom Movement of East, Central and South Africa], 1961-1975 (Box-folder 17: 1)
- Afro-Asian solidarity, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 17: 2)
- African Development Bank, 1964-1975 (Box-folder 17: 3)
- African cooperation-G. R. F. [Garland R. Farmer], 1959-1968 (Box-folder 17: 4)
- Liberian education, 1966-1988 (Box-folder 17: 5)
- Cuttington College materials, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 17: 6)
- University of Liberia School of Business, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 17: 7)
- U.S., Africa official policy and statements, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 18: 1)
- Reports to Liberian government, 1962-1973 (Box-folder 18: 2)
- End MMAL [Mine Management Associates, Ltd.], 1976 (Box-folder 18: 3)
- Miscellaneous Mano, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- World Bank, etc. (later Mano), 1980 (Box-folder 18: 5)
- Mano reports, 1970 (Box-folder 18: 6-7)
- Comparisons with NIOC [National Iron Ore Company], LAMCO [Liberian-American-Swedish Mining Company], Bong (Box-folder 18: 8)
- Correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder 18: 9)
- Correspondence, 1971 (Box-folder 18: 10)
- U.S. - business interests in Africa, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 19: 1)
- U.S.-Africa general trade, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 19: 2)
- U.S. aid policies and programs regarding Africa, 1961-1973 (Box-folder 19: 3)
- U.S. aid to Africa, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 19: 4)
- Black Americans and Africa, 1965-1987 (Box-folder 19: 5)
- U.S. business - banking, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 19: 6)
- U.S.-Africa (education), 1960-1970 (Box-folder 19: 7)
- U.S. - private groups in Africa, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 19: 8)
- California business abroad, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 19: 9)
- U.S. business abroad - general, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 19: 10)
- Council on Foreign Relations, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 19: 11)
- Salaried employees exclusion and complaints, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 20: 1)
- Labor - prior contracts, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 20: 2)
- Industrial Relations Office, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 20: 3)
- Labor disturbances, strikes, complaints, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 20: 4)
- Labor and salaried employees (amenities, fringe benefits, payroll costs), 1966-1972 (Box-folder 20: 5)
- Labor Code, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 20: 6)
- Liberianization, 1964-1977 (Box-folder 20: 7)
- Background memos, labor memo, 1972 (Box-folder 20: 8)
- Possible Liberian personnel, 1971 (Box-folder 20: 9)
- Club Valley, commissary, mess, 1972 (Box-folder 20: 10)
- Government - hospital - doctor - labor, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 20: 11)
- Labor - retirement, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 20: 12)
- Labor - schools, training, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 20: 13)
- Labor negotiations, mainly LMC [Liberia Mining Company], 1964 (Box-folder 20: 14)
- Information on education and training for MMAL [Mine Management Associates, Ltd.], 1964-1966 (Box-folder 20: 15)
- License fee, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 16)
- Mano siliceous fines - sales - information, 1974 (Box-folder 20: 17)
- Employee benefits, 1966 (Box-folder 20: 18)
- James Kankeh, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 20: 19)
- Labor, 1973 (Box-folder 21: 1)
- NIOC [National Iron Ore Company], 1982-1983 (Box-folder 21: 2)
- [Various documents regarding NIOC], undated (Box-folder 21: 3)
- CAEMI International, Inc., 1972-1973 (Box-folder 21: 4)
- NIOC, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 21: 5)
- G. A. P. [George A. Padmore]/NIOC, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 21: 6)
- Labor, 1972 (Box-folder 21: 7)
- Current labor contract, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 21: 8)
- Current personnel matters, 1973 (Box-folder 21: 9)
- Expatriate employees contract, number, etc., 1967-1974 (Box-folder 21: 10)
- General memos on unfinished labor and salaried employees matters, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 21: 11)
- Labor - job classification, productivity, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 21: 12)
- Liberia [articles], 1975-1979 (Box-folder 22: 1-5)
- [Ghana news clippings], 1966-1988 (Box-folder 22: 6)
- Valco/VRA, 1962-1977 (Box-folder 22: 7)
- [Ghana news clippings], 1966-1988 (Box-folder 22: 8)
- [Liberia-related news clippings and documents], 1959-1974, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 23: 1-16)
- Ghana - Kenaf Bag Plant, 1964-1970 (Box-folder 24: 1)
- Ghana - economics, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 24: 2)
- Ghana - African Cooperation OAU [Organization of African Unity], 1960-1965 (Box-folder 24: 3)
- Ghana - Volta River, Kaiser alum, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 24: 4)
- Ghana - foreign policy - U.S., 1961-1965 (Box-folder 24: 5)
- Ghana - newspaper/magazine articles (general - economic), 1970s (Box-folder 24: 6)
- Ghana - economic, 1980s (Box-folder 24: 7)
- Ghana - Soviet Bloc - aid, trade, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 24: 8)
- Ghana - U.S. - aid, trade, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 24: 9)
- Ghana - West (excluding U.S.) - aid, trade, 1962-1976 (Box-folder 24: 10)
- Ghana - foreign relations miscellaneous, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 24: 11)
- Ghana - foreign policy - Africa (excluding African Co-op), 1966-1976 (Box-folder 24: 12)
- Ghana - government and politics, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 24: 13)
- Ghana - foreign policy - Eastern Bloc, 1961-1966 (Box-folder 24: 14)
- Ghana - politics and government (general - political), 1960-1969 (Box-folder 24: 15)
- [Various Ghana news clippings], 1960-1989 (Box-folder 25: 1-2)
- [Map of Ghana], 1970 (Box-folder 25: 3)
- Ghana - history - folklore - culture - art, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 25: 4)
- [Various Ghana documents], 1957-1965 (Box-folder 25: 5)
- Ghana - bibliography, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 25: 6)
- Ghana - general background information, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 25: 7)
- Ghana - investment policies and laws - taxes on business, 1959-1967 (Box-folder 25: 8)
- Ghana - Abbott-Ghana and associated information regarding investment, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 25: 9)
- Ghana - government-owned companies (including nationalization), 1964-1976 (Box-folder 25: 10)
- Western Europe - ore (consumption, requirements, technical considerations), 1974 (Box-folder 26: 1)
- Quality considerations (general market), 1987 (Box-folder 26: 2)
- Technical - sintering, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 26: 3)
- [Information on steel and ore industries], 1988 (Box-folder 26: 4)
- Model iron ore concession, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 5)
- Iron ore projections, 1969-1987 (Box-folder 26: 6)
- Agriculture and investment, 1947-1964 (Box-folder 26: 7)
- Ghana - business and investments, 1961-1983 (Box-folder 26: 8)
- Ghana agriculture, food, timber, 1960-1978 (Box-folder 26: 9)
- Hancock reports, 1987 (Box-folder 27: 1)
- Keall Brindsen/witness statement, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 27: 2)
- Robe River - prices, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 27: 3)
- Australia - prices, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 27: 4)
- Prices - general, 1974-1986 (Box-folder 27: 5)
- Robe River - general, 1975-1987 (Box-folder 27: 6)
- Japan, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 27: 7)
- Iron ore - Africa (excluding Liberia), 1970-1983 (Box-folder 27: 8)
- Iron ore - exports, seaborne trade, 1987 (Box-folder 27: 9)
- Iron ore trade - statistics, general, APEF [Association of Iron Ore Exporting Countries], 1977-1987 (Box-folder 27: 10)
- Iron ore - general, 1958-1986 (Box-folder 27: 11)
- LAMCO [Liberian-American-Swedish Mining Company] documents, 1978-1989 (Box-folder 28: 1)
- Iron ore prices, 1986 (Box-folder 28: 2)
- African iron ore, 1964-1972 (Box-folder 28: 3)
- Mifergui, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 28: 4)
- NIMCO [Nimba International Mining Company] (A. Davies), 1991-1992 (Box-folder 28: 5)
- Liberia mining industry miscellaneous, 1959-1986 (Box-folder 28: 6)
- Liberia - general iron ore statistics, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 28: 7)
- Bong - DELIMCO [German-Liberian Mining Company], 1964-1987 (Box-folder 28: 8)
- Liberia - freight, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 28: 9)
- Iron ore concessions, 1975 (Box-folder 28: 10)
- LAMCO [Liberian-American-Swedish Mining Company] documents, 1960-1980 (Box-folder 29: 1-2)
- LAMCO - general, 1959-1983 (Box-folder 29: 3-4)
- LAMCO financial/dividend ownership, 1958-1969 (Box-folder 29: 5)
- ExChem/J. Baird, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 30: 1)
- Arno Newman/hydro power, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 30: 2)
- Tibor Rosenbaum, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 30: 3)
- Vanply, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 30: 4)
- Liberia - shipping, shipping lines, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 30: 5)
- Steel plant, 1964-1979 (Box-folder 30: 6)
- Refinery, 1963-1990 (Box-folder 30: 7)
- Photographs - opening of LAMCO [Liberian-American-Swedish Mining Company], 1966 (Box-folder 30: 8)
- LAMCO financial documents and memos, 1959-1984 (Box-folder 30: 9)
- Government offices, departments, agencies, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 31: 1)
- Police and military, 1962-1984 (Box-folder 31: 2)
- SCOGO [Special Commission on Government Operations], 1961-1963 (Box-folder 31: 3)
- People's Redemption Council, 1980 (Box-folder 31: 4)
- Business and investment in rubber, agriculture, and timber, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 31: 5)
- Liberia business and investment - laws - government policies - government information, 1964-1985 (Box-folder 31: 6)
- Business - stock offerings, local investment, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 31: 7)
- Leroy Francis, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 31: 8)
- Liberia Company, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 31: 9)
- Mabretuma, Liberian shrimp project, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 31: 10)
- Mesurado, 1966-1987 (Box-folder 31: 11)
- Liberia business and investment - oil (excluding refinery), 1969-1983 (Box-folder 31: 12)
- Ports - Port of Monrovia, World Bank, NPA, charges, 1966-1983 (Box-folder 31: 13)
- Liberia business and investment - foreign, 1960-1987 (Box-folder 31: 14)
- Liberia newspaper industrial supplements, 1971 (Box-folder 31: 15)
- Business and investment - Liberian owned, 1962-1983 (Box-folder 31: 16)
- Padmores, 1974-1990 (Box-folder 32: 1)
- Bishop Harris, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 32: 2)
- A. R. Horton, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 32: 3)
- C. A. Cassell, 1946-1986 (Box-folder 32: 4)
- Hilary Dennis, 1983 (Box-folder 32: 5)
- T. E. Eastman, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 32: 6)
- J. R. Grimes, 1961-1991 (Box-folder 32: 7)
- J. R. G. [J. R. Grimes] - correspondence with G. R. F. [Garland R. Farmer], 1966-1967 (Box-folder 32: 8)
- Miscellaneous non-Liberians, 1966-1984 (Box-folder 32: 9)
- Miscellaneous non-government Liberians, 1966-1987 (Box-folder 32: 10)
- Liberian government officials, 1960s (Box-folder 32: 11)
- Officials and other biographical information, 1970s (Box-folder 32: 12)
- Government officials, 1980s (Box-folder 32: 13)
- National Planning Agency, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 32: 14)
- Various Liberia magazines, 1960-1979 (Box-folder 33: 1)
- Hancock, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 33: 2)
- Wologisi, 1957-1974 (Box-folder 33: 3)
- C. D. Sherman, 1961-1987 (Box-folder 33: 4)
- P. C. Parker, 1963-1974 (Box-folder 33: 5)
- S. Edward Peal, ambassador and senator, 1965-1976 (Box-folder 33: 6)
- [Assorted documents (on iron ore mining)], 1967-1988 (Box-folder 33: 7)
- West African Agricultural Corporation, 1967-1984 (Box-folder 34: 1)
- Vanply/Summit - Liberia, 1966-1983 (Box-folder 34: 2)
- Lofa Logging - C. Weiner, 1973 (Box-folder 34: 3)
- Port of Monrovia charges, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 34: 4)
- Timber industry studies, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 34: 5)
- Port of Monrovia, excluding National Iron Ore Company, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 34: 6)
- Liberian economic reports, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 35: 1)
- Agriculture and COPE [Committee] and operation production, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 35: 2)
- Agrimeco (rice, general), 1973 (Box-folder 35: 3)
- Liberia - Two Cent Program, 1952 (Box-folder 35: 4)
- Miscellaneous Liberian agriculture, 1966-1987 (Box-folder 35: 5)
- Firestone [Tire Company], 1965-1988 (Box-folder 35: 6)
- Sugar/LIBSUCO [Liberian Sugar Company], 1973-1977 (Box-folder 35: 7)
- NIOC [National Iron Ore Company] Board miscellaneous, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 36: 1)
- NIOC Board reports for directors' meetings, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 36: 2)
- NIOC Board meeting minutes, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 36: 3)
- MMAL [Mine Management Associates, Ltd.]-NIOC relationship, 1972 (Box-folder 36: 4)
- U.S. Economic Mission to Liberia, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 36: 5)
- G. F. [Garland Farmer] correspondence, 1965 (Box-folder 37: 1)
- Mano and operating reports, 1965 (Box-folder 37: 2)
- C. Rule operating reports, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 37: 3-4)